# **ALBAN BAILLY**

1346 East Hewson Street, Philadelphia, PA 19125 | (C) 2156090686 | albanbailly@gmail.com

## highlights

Senior Front-end Developer and open source advocate with 8 years of experience. Proven excellence in leading and working in a creative and collaborative environment. Keen observer and solution seeker with a firm belief in the collective good.

#### skills

- Drupal Specialist
- Strong focus on details and problem solving
- Provide code reviews, examine technical requirements and offer tailored solutions
- Provide assistance in the sales process by providing technical consulting for RFPs and/or assist sales meeting
- Expertise in CSS and SASS
- Good knowledge of task builders Gulp, Grunt, Webpack

- Good knowledge of Javascript libraries such as jQuery and React, familiar with Angular
- Good knowledge of Twig
- Comfortable editing object oriented PHP
- Good knowledge of the GIT workflow
- Good knowledge and strong focus on accessibility standards
- Knowledge of the Adobe Creative suite and other design tools such as Sketch and InVision
- Experience in decoupling Drupal 8 with React
- Knowledge of site architecture and site building

# work history

### Senior Front-end Web Developer

May 2013 - Current

7ivtech

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

- Lead Front-end developer for large Drupal releases for clients ranging from small non-profits to nation's leading higher education institutions to pharmaceutical companies
- Provide continued development, maintenance and documentation of new code, bug fixes, and patches for existing web applications
- Assist sales and marketing teams with technical requirements
- Join sales meetings and presentation to prospective and existing clients
- Train, manage, and mentor Junior Developers
- Designed and conducted Drupal 8 Front-end training sessions at national conferences
- Explore, write, and present innovative processes and solutions

Web Developer

- Principal web developer for Wordpress, Drupal, and static web applications, performed SEO and deployments
- Provides Graphic Design services for comps, layouts, and wireframes
- Participated in client meetings and provided estimates

#### Web Developer & Technical Advisor

Jul 2008 - Jun 2010

Simon Group Marketing

Sellersville, Pennsylvania

- Development of custom Drupal solutions and provided technical consulting
- Participated in sales meetings and presentations

Music Instructor Sep 2007 - Jun 2010

The Conservatory

Doylestown, PA

- Private and group instruction on guitar and music
- Organized and managed concerts, master classes, and recording sessions.

#### Composer and Performing Artist

2002 - Current

NA

- Collaborated with international musicians, dancers, and visual artists in Europe and the US as a guitarist and cellist
- Composed and performed for experimental music projects, chamber ensembles, gypsy jazz groups, and contemporary dance productions
- Released albums of original works with established labels as a composer and instrumentalist
- Led national and international tours with multiple ensembles
- Active member of the improvised music community and currently a member of the American Composer
  Forum Philadelphia Chapter

## education

#### Associate of Arts: Jazz Performance and Composition

2003

International Music Academy

Nancy, France

## Associate of Arts: Photography, Cinema and Art History

2001

Université Rennes 2

Rennes, France

# languages

- Full proficiency in spoken and written French
- Basic proficiency in spoken and written German